educationnext.org 2011-06-19

# Privacy Policy : Education Next

### Privacy Policy

Education Next is committed to respecting the privacy of users who access Educationnext.org (the “Site”). This Privacy Policy will tell you (1) what information is collected when you visit our site or send us an email, and (2) how that information is used.

**_Web Server Logs_**

When you visit the Site, our web server may record the following information in its server log:

  * your IP Address,
  * your username (if you have logged in as a registered user),
  * the URLs you have requested to access,
  * the dates and methods of requests,
  * the status code of your requests,
  * URLs of pages that referred you to the Site,
  * number of bytes transferred, and
  * your web browser and operating system platform.

Web server logs are retained on a temporary basis, during which time their contents are accessible to Site administrators, and then deleted completely from our systems. Unless required by legal process, we do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information. This means that user sessions will be tracked by IP address, but a user’s identity will remain anonymous.

In addition, we ordinarily do not disclose to third parties Site usage by individual IP addresses, but we may do so in very limited circumstances when complying with law or legal process, working with consultants assisting us with fixing or improving the Site, or monitoring and improving the security of our network.

**_User Registration_**  
Education Next has adopted a user registration option for visitors who want to post content to the Site or access registration-only pages. To obtain a user registration, you must submit your first name, last name, and email address to Education Next, along with a username and password that you create for user authentication purposes. At your option you may submit a photo as well, but a photo is not required for registration purposes. The Site will include a profile page that will include your first name, last name, username, and, if applicable, your photo. The Site will publish your first and last name alongside any content that you post.

**_Google Analytics_**  
EducationNext.org uses Google Analytics software to perform Site usage analytics. Google Analytics collects anonymous information from users to help Education Next track Site usage and referrals from other websites. These data are used primarily to optimize the website experience for our visitors, but we may use the data as well to assist us in developing marketing plans for the Site.

Information collected and processed by Google Analytics includes the user’s IP address, network location, and geographic location. Google Analytics acquires all its information directly from the user, by installing a cookie (see below) on the user’s computer. The Site does not share any information it collects with Google, and Google Analytics does not collect any personally identifying information such as names, contact information, social security numbers or financial information. Accordingly, we cannot use any information acquired by Google Analytics to contact you directly.

**_Cookies_**  
Cookies are unique bits of computer data that many major websites will transfer to your computer the first time that you visit. Cookies are stored on your hard drive and may be later accessed by the website to track prior usage. As noted above, Google Analytics will install a cookie on the hard drives of Site visitors

In addition, this Site uses WordPress software to process authentication for registered users. WordPress cookies are installed on registered users’ computers when they log in to the site.

**_Email_**  
We will only record your email address if you send us a message or submit it to us as part of the user registration process. We will only use your email address for the purpose for which you have provided it — i.e., to respond to a message from you or to communicate with you regarding your user account.

When you submit your email address to the Site during registration, Education Next will ask you whether you want to receive periodic announcements from the Site by email. Accepting emailed announcements is entirely optional and not a condition of registration, and you may change your email settings at any time to subscribe or “unsubscribe” to these mailings.

Any feedback emailed to us using our [“Contact Us”](http://www.educationext.org/sub/contact/) button will be used for site performance evaluation only.

**_Disclosure to Third Parties_**  
We will not sell, lend, or disclose to third parties any information collected from visitors, except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy or in the event we are required by law to do so. We may disclose information to employees, consultants and agents who have a legitimate need to know the information for the purpose of fixing or improving the Site and monitoring and improving the security of our network. We also reserve the right to disclose this information when special circumstances call for it, such as when disclosure is required by law or court order or when disclosure is, in our sole discretion, necessary to protect our legal rights, including intellectual property rights.

**_Other Websites_**  
This Site may contain links to other web resources, including websites of organizations other than Education Next and third-party vendors that conduct sales transactions on behalf of Education Next. The websites of our advertisers, vendors, and other websites to which the Site links may also collect user-identifying information directly from you once you proceed to browse those sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of our advertisers, sponsors, vendors or other sites or businesses to which we provide hyperlinks or access. Please visit the relevant sites to review their privacy policies.

_**Data Security**_  
We have in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. However, as effective as these measures are, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot completely guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

**_Notification of Changes in the Privacy Policy_**  
We will review our security measures and Privacy Policy on a periodic basis, and we may modify our policies as appropriate. We may also change or update our Privacy Policy if we add new services or features. If any changes are made, we will make appropriate amendments to this policy and post them at the Site. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy on a regular basis.

**_Effective Date_**  
This Privacy Policy is in effect as of August 14, 2009.

##### Sponsored Results

The Hoover Institution at Stanford University - Ideas Defining a Free Society

Harvard Kennedy School Program on Educational Policy and Governance

Thomas Fordham Institute - Advancing Educational Excellence and Education Reform

##### Sign Up To Receive Notification

when the latest issue of Education Next is posted

In the meantime check the site regularly for new articles, blog postings, and reader comments
